<resources>
    <string name="app_name">ZOO_APPLICATION</string>
    <!-- Preference Titles -->
    <string name="messages_header">Messages</string>
    <string name="sync_header">Sync</string>

    <!-- Messages Preferences -->
    <string name="signature_title">Your signature</string>
    <string name="reply_title">Default reply action</string>

    <!-- Sync Preferences -->
    <string name="sync_title">Sync email periodically</string>
    <string name="attachment_title">Download incoming attachments</string>
    <string name="attachment_summary_on">Automatically download attachments for incoming emails
    </string>
    <string name="attachment_summary_off">Only download attachments when manually requested</string>

    <string name="navigation_drawer_open">Open navigation drawer</string>
    <string name="navigation_drawer_close">Close navigation drawer</string>
    <string name="kidslion">The lion is a large mammal found in India and Africa. They belong to the carnivorous type, preying on other animals for their food. Male lions are larger than females (lionesses), and they have a mane growing on them. Most of the lions are brownish-yellow in colour, and are considered the king of the jungles. Lions represent bravery and royalty, so they are mentioned in various flags, folklore, and literary work.</string>
    <string name="adultslion">The lion (Panthera leo) is a hefty carnivorous mammal native to Africa and India. It has a muscular, deep-chested body, short, rounded head, round ears, and a hairy tuft at the end of its tail. Adult male lions are more significant than females and have a prominent mane. Lions normally behave forming groups called prides. A lion\'s pride consists of a few adult males, related females, and cubs. Groups of female lions usually hunt together, preying primarily on large mammals. Typically, the lion inhabits grasslands but is absent in dense forests. They\'ve been on the course of extinction since 1996 as populations in African countries have declined by about 43% since the early 1990s. Habitat loss and conflicts with humans are the greatest threats to concern. One of the most widely recognized animal symbols in human culture, the lion, has been extensively depicted in sculptures and paintings, national flags, and contemporary films and literature. A full-grown male lion measures around 72-82 inches and weighs around 180kgs. In comparison, a lioness is much smaller, which weighs around 120kgs and extends up to 63-72 inches. The male lion\'s mane is the most recognizable feature of the species. It starts growing when lions are about a year old. Lionesses go hunting most of the time while the males rest throughout the day; they are inactive for about twenty hours per day.</string>
    <string name="kidsdeer">Spotted deer are a yellowish-brown colored mammal that feeds on tree shoots and bushes. They get the name \"spotted deer\" as their bodies are covered with white color spots. Male spotted deers are larger than females, and they have antlers to protect themselves. The spotted deer is a common sight in natural parks, forests, and zoos in Asia. The greatest threat to spotted deer are humans who hunt them for sport and carnivores such as lions, tigers, leopards, and hyenas.</string>
    <string name="adultsdeer">\"The spotted deer, also known as chital, chital deer, and axis deer, is a species of deer that is native to the Indian subcontinent. They belong to the herbivore segment of mammals and mainly feeds on tree shoots and bushes. They were first described by German naturalist Johann Christian Polycarp Erxleben in 1777. A moderate-sized deer, the male spotted-deer reach nearly 35 inches and females 28 inches at the shoulder. While males weigh 30–75 kg, the lighter females weigh 25–45 kg. Males are larger than females, and antlers are present only on males. Antlers are used for display and as a weapon, and they sharpen them by rubbing on tree trunks.  The upper parts of the spotted deer take a golden-brownish color, completely covered in white spots. The abdomen, rump, throat, insides of legs, ears, and tail are all white. Their antlers are nearly 3.3 feet long. The tail is around 7.9 inches long and is marked by a dark stripe that stretches along its length. The spotted deer are usually active throughout the day. They rest under the shade in the summer to avoid the sun\'s glare as the temperature rises more than 27 °C. Hence, their activity peaks as the dusk approaches. Spotted deers are common in the Dehiwala Zoo and all around the natural parks and wilderness throughout Asia. The greatest threat to spotted deer are humans who hunt them for sport and carnivores such as lions, tigers, leopards, and hyenas.   \"</string>
    <string name="kidspelican">The pelican is a large bird with a unique pouch-shaped beak, which is used to catch prey and drain water from scooped up contents before swallowing. Their primary food source is fish. Pelicans turn brightly colored during their mating season. They are said to be living since before 30 million years. Pelicans live near inland and coastal waterways where they can find food with ease. The main threats to Pelicans are habitat destruction and environmental pollution.</string>
    <string name="adultspelican">Pelicans are a genus of large water birds that make up the family Pelecanidae. They are characterized by a long beak and a large throat pouch used to catch prey and drain water from the scooped-up contents before swallowing. They have predominantly pale plumage, except for the brown and Peruvian pelicans. All pelicans\' bills, pouches, and bare facial skin become brightly coloured before the breeding season. Fossil evidence of pelicans dates back at least 30 million years to the remains of a beak very similar to that of modern species recovered from Oligocene strata in France. Pelicans are frequent in inland and coastal waters, where they feed primarily on fish, catching them at or near the water surface. They travel in flocks, hunting cooperatively and breeding colonially. Their populations have fallen through habitat destruction, disturbance, and environmental pollution, and three species out of seven are of conservation concern. They also have a long history of cultural significance in mythology and Christian and heraldic iconography.</string>
    <string name="kidstiger">The tiger is a large mammal found mainly in Asia. They belong to the carnivorous type, preying on other animals for food. They have very sharp teeth for this purpose. Male tigers are about two times larger than females tigers. Most tigers are golden-yellowish in color and have black stripes in regular intervals. Tigers can climb trees, run fast and swim very well. Humans hunt tigers for their skin.</string>
    <string name="adultstiger">The tiger is a carnivorous mammal mainly found in the Asian continent. Most tigers consist of golden-yellowish fur with black patterned stripes in regular intervals. This color pattern helps them to camouflage while moving through the wilderness. Generally, a full-grown male tiger extent 8.2 to 12.8 ft in length and weigh between 90 and 300 kgs. Females vary from 6.56 to 9.02 ft in length and weigh 65 to 167 kgs. Tigers prey on land animals it does not often climb trees, but cases have been recorded. They are good swimmers and often bathes in ponds, lakes, and rivers, thus keeping cool in the heat of the day. Individuals can cross rivers up to 7 km wide and can swim up to 29 km in a day. Tigers mainly feed on large and medium-sized mammals in the wild, particularly sambar deers and wild boars. Monkeys are also considered prey of tigers, but cases are rarely reported. Tigers are thought to be mainly nocturnal predators. The main threat to tigers is hunters, as their skin holds a high value in the market. As a result, the tigers are on course to becoming extinct from the face of planet Earth.</string>
    <string name="kidselephant">The Asian elephant is the largest land animal in Asia. Elephants are black. They have a long nose called “trunk,” two large ears, and a large body. Some elephants have two large teeth, which are known as “tusks.” Tusks are used as a weapon and to display their strength. Elephants are an endangered animal as humans kill them for their tusks and skin.</string>
    <string name="adultselephant">The Asian elephant is the largest living land animal in Asia. They have been listed as Endangered since 1986, considering the population decrease by at least 50% over the last 60–75 years. The Asian elephant is smaller than the African bush elephant. A fully-grown male elephant is about 2.75 m tall and weighs around 4 tonnes, while the females are smaller at about 2.40 m and 2.7 tonnes in weight. The trunk is the unique part of an elephant made by elongation of the nose and upper lip combined. Its length may vary from 1.5 to 2 m. Some elephants are gifted with tusks, which dig for water, salt, and rocks, hard maneuvering, display, and weapon for offense and defense. The most concerning threats to the Asian Elephant are habitat loss, habitat degradation, fragmentation, and poaching.</string>


</resources>